Guide to the Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne papers vvb
University of Michigan Library (Special Collections Research Center)
- Correspondence
  - Name File
    - Dinsmore, H. B. (Box 6)
    - Donat, Robert (Box 6)
    - Doolittle, Hilda (Box 6)
    - Dowell, George Brendan (Box 6)
    - Drage, Robert L. (Box 6)
    - Drama League of America (Box 6)
    - Dransfield, Jane (Box 6)
    - Drinkwater, John (Box 6)
    - Dukes, Ashley (Box 6)
    - Dukore, Bernard Frank (Box 6)
    - Dunbar, Neen (Box 6)
    - Dunne, Edward Fitzsimmons (Box 6)
    - Dunnock, Mildred (Box 6)
    - Dyne, Michael (Box 6)
    - Earle, Beatrice (Lowndes) (Box 6)
    - Earp, R. W. (Box 6)
    - Eastman, Max (Box 6)
    - Edgerton, Harriet (Box 6)
    - Edstrom, David (Box 6)
    - Edwards, Cyril A.
      Also known as Arnold Moon.
      - Outgoing correspondence, 1946-1965 (Box 6)
        To Maurice (and Molly) Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg (1946-1962) and to others, concerning Edwards's whereabouts (1962-1965).
      - Works
        - Collected loose poems, 1937-1939 and undated (Box 6)
        - Manuscripts
          - "Myria Dummler", undated (Box 6)
          - "Remarks on Structure of Space and Time", undated (Box 6)
          - "The Building", undated (Box 6)
          - "The Triumph of Hate: Play", ca. 1952 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous writings and print, 1949-1961 and undated (Box 6)
    - Eggeman, Caroline (Box 7)
    - Ellis, Edith Mary Oldham (Lees) (Box 7)
    - Eliot, Peter (Box 7)
    - Ellegood, Donald R. (Box 7)
    - Ellet, R. E. (Box 7)
    - Ellis, Havelock (Box 7)
    - Ellis, Richenda (Box 7)
    - Elmhirst Family (Box 7)
    - Elmhirst, Dorothy (Whitney)
      - Incoming correspondence
        - Browne, Maurice, 1937-1952 (Box 7)
          Chiefly concerning his autobiography.
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, 1933-1938 (Box 7)
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, 1929-1968 (Box 7)
        - General correspondence, 1926-1966 and undated (Box 7)
      - Condolence letters, 1969 (Box 7)
        To Ellen Van Volkenburg, regarding Dorothy Elmhirst. From various senders.
    - Elmhirst, Leonard Knight, 1951 and undated (Box 7)
      Outgoing correspondence, including a poem.
    - Emery, Pollie (Box 7)
    - Engel, Lehman (Box 7)
    - Ensor, Aubrey (Box 7)
    - Enters, Angna (Box 7)
    - Epstein, J. (Box 7)
    - Erichson, Richard (Box 7)
    - Ervine, St. John Grerr (Box 7)
    - Evans, Dame Edith (Box 7)
    - Evans, Julius (Box 7)
    - Evans, Maurice (Box 7)
    - Evans-Curtis, John (Box 7)
    - Everest, Barbara (Box 7)
    - Ewing, Rose D. (Box 7)
    - Fagan, Elisabeth (Box 7)
    - Fagan, James Bernard (Box 7)
    - Favard, Bertha des Combes (Box 7)
    - Faversham, William (Box 7)
    - Fayne, Arthur (Box 7)
    - Feakins, William B. (Box 7)
    - Ffrangcon-Davies, Gwen (Box 7)
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison
      - Correspondence
        - Incoming correspondence
          - Browne, Maurice
            - List of Microfilm Copies, undated (Box 7)
            - Original Letters, 1905-1937; 4 folders (Box 7)
          - Evans, Donald, ca. 1921-1957 (Box 7)
          - Monro, Harold, 1907 (Box 7)
          - Monroe, Harriet, 1916 (Box 7)
        - Outgoing correspondence
          - Browne, Maurice, 1905-1927, 1931-1937, and undated; 5 folders (Box 7)
          - Powys, John Cowper, 1936-1944 (Box 7)
            Photocopies. Originals held by the Beinecke Library, Yale University.
          - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, 1921-1937 (Box 7)
          - Roosevelt, F. D., 1939 (Box 7)
        - Browne, Maurice (Box 7)
          Correspondence regarding Arthur Davison Ficke.
        - Wistach, John (Box 7)
      - Inscriptions, 1939 (Box 7)
      - Manuscripts
        - "Beloved Land", undated (Box 7)
        - "The Birthday Celebration", 1949? (Box 7)
          Received by Maurice Browne from Mrs. Ficke in 1949.
        - "The Epistle of St. Arthur Unto the Thibetans" (Box 7)
        - "Ether", 1918 (Box 7)
        - From the Isles, 1907 (Box 7)
        - The Happy Princes: A Romance, ca. 1907 (Box 7)
          With comments in pencil by Maurice Browne, 1907.
        - The Lord of Asia, 1930 (Box 7)
        - Mr. Faust, undated (Box 7)
          Copy 1.
        - Mr. Faust, undated (Box 7)
          Copy 2.
        - "Portrait of a Woman by Yeishi", undated (Box 7)
        - Seven Sonnets to Maurice Browne, undated (Box 7)
        - The Sins of the Fathers, ca. 1937 (Box 7)
          Third draft.
        - Sonnets of a Portrait Painter, ca. 1914 (Box 7)
          Original drafts.
        - "Swinburne: An Elegy", undated (Box 7)
        - "The Tomb of His Ancestors", undated (Box 7)
        - "Tribute to Greatness", undated (Box 7)
        - "Ye English and Irish", ca. 1913 (Box 7)
        - Miscellaneous poems, 1927 and undated (Box 7)
        - Poems: clippings, 1908-1943 and undated (Box 7)
    - Ficke, Gladys
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Browne, Maurice, 1945-1953 (Box 7)
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, 1948-1955 (Box 7)
    - Field, Marion L. (Box 7)
    - Field, Sara Bard (Box 7)
    - Finch, Lucine (Box 7)
    - Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor (Box 7)
    - Flavin, Martin (Box 7)
    - Flint, Frank Stewart (Box 7)
    - Fogarty, Elsie (Box 7)
    - Foley, Ida (Box 7)
    - Ford, Sir Edward William Spencer (Box 7)
    - Foulger, Byron Kay (Box 7)
    - Fox-Strangeways, Sylvia, 1955-1967 (Box 7)
      Letters and poems to Ellen Van Volkenburg and Molly Underwood, including drawings and watercolor decorations.
    - Fraser, E. Dolly (Box 7)
    - Fraser, Marjory (Kennedy) (Box 7)
    - Free, Marion Allen (Box 7)
    - Freedley, George (Box 7)
    - Freeman, Helen (Box 7)
    - Freund, Frank E. Washburn (Box 7)
    - Frith, J. Leslie (Box 7)
    - Fry, Christopher
      - Correspondence (Box 7)
      - Siege: A Comedy in Three Acts (Box 7)
    - Fuller, Cynthia (Box 7)
    - Fuller, Rosalinde (Box 7)
    - Fuller, Walter G. (Box 7)
    - Galantière, Lewis (Box 7)
    - Gale, Zona (Box 7)
    - Galsworthy, John (Box 7)
    - Galway, Margaret (Box 7)
    - Game, Henry Clement (Box 7)
    - Garland, Hamlin (Box 7)
    - Garson, Greer (Box 7)
    - Gates, Robert (Box 7)
    - Geddes, Norman Bel (Box 7)
    - Gerstenberg, Alice (Box 7)
    - Gest, Morris (Box 7)
    - Gibson, Elizabeth Cheyne
      - Correspondence, 1907 (Box 7)
      - Works, 1907 and undated (Box 7)
    - Gibson, Wilfrid Wilson, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Correspondence, 1905-1953; 2 folders (Box 8)
      - Works
        - Fires, undated (Box 8)
        - On the Threshold
          - On the Threshold typescript (incomplete), undated (Box 8)
          - On the Threshold proof sheets, 1907 (Box 8)
        - The Web of Life
          - The Web of Life typescript (printer's copy), undated (Box 8)
          - The Web of Life proof sheets and specimen pages, undated (Box 8)
          - The Web of Life page proofs, 1908 (Box 8)
    - Gielgud, Sir John (Box 8)
    - Gielgud, Val Henry (Box 8)
    - Gill, Eric (Box 8)
    - Gillmore, Frank (Box 8)
    - Gladstone, Hurbert (Box 8)
    - Glaspell, Susan (Box 8)
    - Glen, John E. (Box 8)
    - Glover, Halcott (Box 8)
    - Ginsbury, Norman (Box 8)
    - Goggs, M. S. Russell (Box 8)
    - Gollancz, Victor (Box 8)
    - Golding, Louis (Box 8)
    - Goldman, Emma (Box 8)
    - Good, Edward (Box 8)
    - Goodman, Esther Regeena (Box 8)
    - Goodrich, John Fish (Box 8)
    - Goodyear, Conger (Box 8)
    - Gordon, Irene (Box 8)
    - Gosse, Sir Edmund William (Box 8)
    - Goudge, Elizabeth (Box 8)
    - Graham, E. A. (Box 8)
    - Granville-Barker, Harley
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - LeRoy, Alma, ca. 1915 (Box 8)
        - Browne, Maurice, 1913-1920 (Box 8)
        - Browne, Frances A. Neligan, 1924 (Box 8)
    - Graves, Charles (Box 8)
    - Gray, Terence (Box 8)
    - Great Britain. Lord Chamberlain's Office (Box 8)
    - Green, Paul (Box 8)
    - Greene, Alexander
      - Correspondence
        - Outgoing correspondence
          - Browne, Maurice, 1924, 1939 (Box 8)
          - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, 1928-1947 (Box 8)
          - Van Volkenburg, Mrs. F. H., 1935 (Box 8)
        - Incoming correspondence, 1919-1927 (Box 8)
          From Maurice Browne.
      - "A Rainbow in the West", undated (Box 8)
        Under the name Alesander Belshaw.
      - Ana, 1935 and undated (Box 8)
    - Greene, Mary (Box 8)
    - Greene-Armitage, R. N. (Box 8)
    - Greet, Sir Ben (Box 8)
    - Gregory, Alyse, 1946-1954 (Box 8)
      Outgoing correspondence to Maurice Browne.
    - Gregory, Isabella Augusta (Persse), lady (Box 8)
    - Griffith, Margaret (Box 8)
    - Guglielmo, C. (Box 8)
    - Guthrie, James Joshua
      - Correspondence (Box 8)
        General correspondence and correspondence to A. Sabin.
      - Works (Box 8)
    - Gutkind, Eric (Box 8)
    - Gwatkin, Fred A. (Box 8)
    - Hagedorn, Hermann
      Regarding his poem, The Bomb That Fell on America.
      - Outgoing correspondence and writings
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen ("Josh"), 1946 (Box 8)
        - Browne, Maurice, 1946 (Box 8)
      - The Bomb That Fell on America, 1945-1950; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Haggard, Stephen (Box 8)
    - Haig, Dorothy Maud (Vivian) Haig, countess (Box 8)
    - Hall, Hazel (Box 8)
    - Hall, O. L. (Box 8)
    - Hambourg, Boris (Box 8)
    - Hamilton, Cosmo (Box 8)
    - Hamilton, Dollie (Box 8)
    - Hamilton, Edith (Box 8)
    - Hamilton, Hamish (Box 8)
    - Hamilton, Jean D. (Box 8)
    - Hammond, Emily Vanderbilt (Sloane) (Box 8)
    - Hampden, Walter (Box 8)
    - Hannen, Nicholas James (Box 8)
    - Hardwicke, Sir Cedric (Box 8)
    - Hargreaves, Reginald (Box 8)
    - Harlech, William George Arthur Ormsby-Gore, baron (Box 8)
    - Harris, E. Tegan (Box 8)
    - Harris, Fay (Box 8)
    - Harris, Frank (Box 8)
    - Hart, Annie (Box 8)
    - Hart, T. (Box 8)
    - Harvey, Sir John Martin (Box 8)
    - Harwood, Harold Marsh (Box 8)
    - Haskell, Arnold Lionel (Box 8)
    - Haskell, Gilman (Box 8)
    - Hasker, Gordon (Box 8)
    - Hassett, William D. (Box 8)
    - Hasso, Signe (Larssen) (Box 8)
    - Hathaway, C. S. (Box 8)
    - Hatlen, Theodore Wendell (Box 8)
    - Hatton, Fanny Cottinet (Locke) (Box 8)
    - Hatton, Frederic (Box 8)
    - Head, Cloyd (Box 8)
    - Headfort, Rosie (Box 8)
    - Heggie, O. P. (Box 8)
    - Hely-Hutchinson, Victor (Box 8)
    - Henderson, Elizabeth Perry (Faulkner) (Box 8)
    - Henson, Leslie Lincoln (Box 8)
    - Hepburn, Katharine (Box 8)
    - Herbert, Gwen (Box 8)
    - Heriot, Adelaide (Box 8)
    - Herndon, Richard G. (Box 8)
    - Heymann, Elsa Paul (Box 8)
    - Hicks, Sir Seymour (Box 8)
    - Hight, Arthur E. (Box 8)
    - Hill, Dorothy (Box 8)
    - Hill, Dorothy Elizabeth (Browne)
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Van Volkenburg, Mrs. F. H., 1914 (Box 8)
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, 1928-1957 (Box 8)
        - Browne, Francis Anna, and Browne, Maurice, 1905 and undated (Box 8)
    - Hill, Robert (Box 8)
    - Hill, Robert (G. A.) (Box 8)
    - Hills, Ross (Box 8)
    - Hoard, Bessie B. (Box 8)
    - Hoff, Margo (Box 8)
    - Holländer, Vera (Box 8)
    - Hopkins, Arthur Melancthon (Box 8)
    - Hopkins, Charles (Box 8)
    - Hopper, De Wolf (Box 8)
    - Horne, David (Box 8)
    - Horrabin, J. A. (Box 8)
    - Houghton, Norris (Box 8)
    - Housman, Laurence (Box 8)
    - Howard, Lawrence (Box 8)
    - Howell, Miriam Olive (Box 8)
    - Hsiung, Shih-I (Box 8)
    - Hubbard, Elbert (Box 8)
    - Hudd, Walter (Box 8)
    - Hudson, Christine (Box 8)
    - Hudson, Derek (Box 8)
    - Huebsch, Benjamin W. (Box 8)
    - Hunter, Mary T. (Box 8)
    - Hutchinson, E. W. (Box 8)
    - Huxley, Aldous Leonard (Box 8)
    - Inge, Mary Catherine (Spooner) (Box 8)
    - Inglis, Phyllis (Box 8)
    - Isherwood, Margaret (Box 8)
    - Ivan, Rosalind (Box 8)
    - Jackson, Sir Barry Vincent (Box 8)
    - James, William, 1953 (Box 8)
    - Jameson, Storm (Box 8)
    - Jeffers, Robinson (Box 8)
    - Jenison, Madge (Box 8)
    - Jenison, Nancy (Box 8)
    - Joel, Jack (Box 8)
    - Johnson, Martyn (Box 8)
    - Jones, Barry (Box 8)
    - Jones, Margo (Box 8)
    - Jones, Robert Edmond (Box 8)
    - Jonez, Bernice (Box 8)
    - Jonson, Raymond (Box 8)
    - Jonson, Vera (White) (Box 8)
    - Jordan, Jo ("J. J.")
      - Incoming correspondence, May 11, 1969-August 18, 1969; 2 folders (Box 8)
        From Ellen Van Volkenburg.
      - Outgoing correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
        To Ellen Van Volkenburg.
      - Journals, manuscripts, and memorabilia, 1968-1971 (Box 8)
        Includes a photograph of Molly Underwood.
    - Joseph, Helen (Haiman) (Box 8)
    - Joseph, Nannine (Box 8)
    - Jouvet, Louis (Box 8)
    - Kallen, Horace Meyer (Box 9)
    - Kanéllos, Vássos (Box 9)
    - Karsavina, Tamara (Box 9)
    - Keane, Doris (Box 9)
    - Keen, Herbert F. (Box 9)
    - Keenan, De Elbert (Box 9)
    - Kelsch, Beulah (Box 9)
    - Kennedy, Charles Rann (Box 9)
    - Kennedy, Mary (Box 9)
    - Kent, Kenneth (Box 9)
    - Kerlin, Fentress Saurin (Box 9)
    - Kerton, Louise (Box 9)
    - Keynes, J. M. (Box 9)
    - King-Hall, Stephen (Box 9)
    - Kingston, Gertrude (Box 9)
    - Kitchin, Laurence (Box 9)
    - Knights, Phyllis W. (Box 9)
    - Koĭranskiĭ (Box 9)
    - Komai, Gonnoskè (Box 9)
    - Korda, Sir Alexander (Box 9)
    - Kreymborg, Alfred (Box 9)
    - Krishna, Mēnōn, Vengalil Krishnan (Box 9)
    - Kuster, Edward G. (Box 9)
    - Lacey, Catherine T. (Miser) (Box 9)
    - Ladue, Mary Newberry (Box 9)
    - Lally, Gwen (Box 9)
    - Lambe, John Lawrence (Box 9)
    - Lamm, Olof Herman (Box 9)
    - Lang, Matheson (Box 9)
    - Langner, Armina (Marshall) (Box 9)
    - Langner, Lawrence (Box 9)
    - Langston, Basil C. (Box 9)
    - Larsen, Thorvald (Box 9)
    - Laughton, Charles (Box 9)
    - Laurie, John (Box 9)
    - Leach, Bernard Howell (Box 9)
    - Leblanc, Georgette (Box 9)
    - Lees, Madeline (Pelly), Lady (Box 9)
    - Leigh, W. Colston (Box 9)
    - Leith-Hay-Clark, Norman (Box 9)
    - Leonard, William Ellery (Box 9)
    - Lester, Gertrude (Box 9)
    - Levy, José G. (Box 9)
    - Lewis, Cecil (Box 9)
    - Leyssac, Paul (Box 9)
    - Lindo, Olga (Box 9)
    - Lindsay, Nicholas Vachel (Box 9)
    - Ling, Barbara (Box 9)
    - Lion, Leon M. (Box 9)
    - Litchfield, M. H. (Box 9)
    - Livingstone, Dame Adelaide Lord (Stickney) (Box 9)
    - Livingstone, Sir Richard Winn (Box 9)
    - Löhr, Marie (Box 9)
    - Long, Georgia (Box 9)
    - Long, Haniel (Daniel?) (Box 9)
    - Loraine, Robert (Box 9)
    - Lovell, Raymond (Box 9)
    - Lucas, Ethel M. (Box 9)
    - Lüttichau, Curt (Box 9)
    - Lundquist, Frances (Box 9)
    - Lunt, Cornelia Gray (Box 9)
    - Luther, Calvin (Box 9)
      In the hand of Mrs. F. H. Van Volkenburg.
    - Luther, Lester (Box 9)
    - Macauley, Thurston, 1922 (Box 9)
    - McBey, Marguerite Huntsberry, 1937 (Box 9)
    - McCoole, Paul (Box 9)
    - McCracken, Esther Helen (Armstrong), 1938 (Box 9)
    - Macdougall, Allan Ross, 1953 (Box 9)
    - MacDowell, Marian Griswold (Nevins), 1926 (Box 9)
    - McGaw, Emma (Mrs. Baldwine McGaw), 1955? (Box 9)
    - Macgowan, Kenneth (Box 9)
    - McGrath, Paul, undated (Box 9)
    - Macintyre, Ida P., 1955 (Box 9)
    - MacKaye, Percy (Box 9)
    - Maclachlan, Leeh D., 1929 (Box 9)
    - MacLeod, Josephine, 1932-1946 (Box 9)
    - McLorn, Olive (Box 9)
    - McManamy, Monica, 1955 (Box 9)
    - MacOwan, Michael, 1946 (Box 9)
    - McPharlin, Paul (Box 9)
    - Macy, Gertrude Marguerite, 1949 (Box 9)
    - Major, Stella (Perugini), 1955 (Box 9)
    - Malleson, Lady Constance, 1936 (Box 9)
    - Malleson, Miles, 1934 (Box 9)
    - Maltby, Henry Francis, 1930 (Box 9)
    - Mannin, Ethel Edith, 1930 (Box 9)
    - Mansford, Wallis, 1937? (Box 9)
    - Markham, Emily, 1938-1947 (Box 9)
      Includes photographs.
    - Markham, Kyra, 1966 (Box 9)
    - Marks, Jeannette Augustus, 1916-1921 and undated (Box 9)
    - Marks, Seymour, 1934 (Box 9)
    - Marmein, Irene, 1956 (Box 9)
    - Marmein, Miriam, 1955 (Box 9)
    - Marsh, Sir Edward Howard (Box 9)
    - Martin, John Joseph (Box 9)
    - Martin, John Joseph, and Martin, Louis (Mrs. John Joseph Martin), 1935-1955 (Box 9)
    - Marton, George, 1930 (Box 9)
    - Marx, Erica, 1953 (Box 9)
    - Masefield, John, 1930 and undated (Box 9)
    - Masters, Edgar Lee (Box 9)
    - Mathews, Dorothy, 1956 (Box 9)
    - Matthias, Blance, and Matthias, Russell, 1955 (Box 9)
    - Mavor, Osborne Henry, 1932-1938 (Box 9)
    - Maxton, James, 1938 (Box 9)
    - Maxtone Graham, Joyce (Anstruther), 1930 (Box 9)
    - Maxwell, J. G., 1928 (Box 9)
    - Mei Lan-fang, 1935-1937 (Box 9)
    - Menges, Herbert, undated (Box 9)
    - Mercier, Jean, 1929 (Box 9)
    - Merriam, Harold Guy, 1949 (Box 9)
    - Miles, Eustace Hamilton, 1949 (Box 9)
    - Miller, Gilbert Heron, 1930-1934 (Box 9)
    - Milne, Alan Alexander, 1938? (Box 9)
    - Minshall, Edward, 1928 (Box 9)
    - Miramova, Elena, 1936-1969 (Box 9)
    - Monro, Alida (Klemantaski), 1928-1932 (Box 9)
    - Monro, Harold, 1879-1932
      - Correspondence
        - Incoming correspondence from Maurice Browne, 1902-1912; 4 folders (Box 9)
        - Outgoing correspondence
          - Browne, Frances A., 1913 (Box 9)
          - Browne, Maurice, 1902-1912, 1914-1916, 1923-1929; 4 folders (Box 9)
      - Ana, 1910-1982 and undated (Box 9)
        Information about H. Monroe by M. Browne and others.
    - Monroe, Harriet (Box 9)
    - Montizambert, Elizabeth, 1928-1932 (Box 9)
    - Moore, Alberta E., undated (Box 9)
    - Moore, Raymond, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Morel, Paula, 1930 (Box 9)
    - Morgan, Charles, 1932-1934 and undated (Box 9)
    - Morgenstern, Connie M., 1955 (Box 9)
    - Morland, Nigel, 1930 (Box 9)
    - Morley, Henry, 5 folders
      Materials related to Maurice Browne's attempted revision of Morley's A First Sketch of English Literature.
      - Correspondence
        - Agresti, Olivia Rossetti, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Austin, Alfred, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Bax, Ernest Belfort, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Bland, Edith (Nesbit), 1909 (Box 9)
        - Clodd, Edward, undated (Box 9)
        - Courtney, William Leonard, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Darwin, Sir Francis, undated (Box 9)
        - Forman, Harry Buxton, undated (Box 9)
        - Galton, Sir Francis, undated (Box 9)
        - Geikie, Sir Archibald, undated (Box 9)
        - Geikie, James, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Gilbert, Sir William, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Gould, Frederick James, undated (Box 9)
        - Harrison, Frederic, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Hawkins, Sir Anthony Hope, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Hewlett, Maurice Henry, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Kidd, Benjamin, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Lang, Andrew, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Lee, Sir Sidney, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Lee, Vernon (pseudonym) (see Paget, Violet) (Box 9)
        - Lodge, Sir Oliver Joseph, 1910 (Box 9)
        - Money, Sir Leo George Chiozza, undated (Box 9)
        - Murray, Gilbert, undated (Box 9)
        - Noyes, Alfred, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Paget, Violet, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Passfield, Sidney James Webb, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Payne, John, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Phillpotts, Eden, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Robertson, John Mackinnon, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Rossetti, William Michael, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Saleeby, Caleb Williams, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Trench, Herbert, 1909 (Box 9)
        - Waddington, Samuel, 1910 (Box 9)
        - Watts-Dunton, Theodore, 1909 and undated (Box 9)
      - Morley's First Sketch, 1936, 1948 (Box 9)
        Morley's A First Sketch of English Literature, later papers.
    - Morton, Robert, 1938-1942 (Box 9)
    - Moseman, Edward, and Moseman, Anne, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
    - Moulton, Richard Green, 1914-1917 (Box 9)
    - Mowatt, Glossentine, 1954 (Box 9)
    - Muni, Paul, 1934 (Box 9)
    - Murray, Douglas, 1930 (Box 9)
    - Murray, Gilbert
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Browne, Maurice, 1912-1952 (Box 9)
        - Browne, Mrs. F. H., 1924 (Box 9)
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, 1920-1928 (Box 9)
    - Murray, Lady Mary Henrietta (Howard), 1914-1930 (Box 9)
      Outgoing correspondence to Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne.
    - Napier, Nan, 1934 (Box 9)
    - Nash, Paul, undated (Box 9)
    - National Council of Social Service, 1941 (Box 9)
    - Neebe, Jos. H., undated (Box 9)
    - Neill, Alexander Sutherland, 1935 (Box 9)
    - Neligan, Jill, 1932 (Box 9)
    - Neligan, Mary Mcrory ("Aunt May") (Box 9)
    - Nesbitt, Cathleen, 1958 and undated (Box 9)
    - Newman, Chaim, 1943 (Box 9)
    - Ney, Marie, August 31 (Box 9)
    - Nichols, Beverley, 1930-1933 and undated (Box 9)
    - Nichols, Norah (Box 9)
    - Nichols, Robert Malise Bowyer
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Browne, Maurice, 1923-1944 and undated; 3 folders (Box 9)
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, 1930 (Box 9)
      - Poems, 1927-1931 and undated (Box 9)
      - Ana, 1931-1944 and undated (Box 9)
    - Nield, Hilda M. K. (Box 10)
    - Nordfeldt, Bror Julius Olsson, and Nordfeldt, Margaret D. (Box 10)
    - Norman, Norman V. (Box 10)
    - Nortin, George (Box 10)
    - Norton, Charles W. (Box 10)
    - Novello, Ivor (Box 10)
    - Obey, André (Box 10)
    - O'Brien, Edward Joseph Harrington (Box 10)
    - O'Casey, Sean (Box 10)
    - Odlin, Reno, and Odlin, Edith Murphy (Heston) (Box 10)
    - Odlin, Richard (Box 10)
    - Oenslager, Donald (Box 10)
    - Ogden, Charles Kay (Box 10)
    - O'Hara, Frank Herbert (Box 10)
    - Olivier, Laurence Kerr (Box 10)
    - O'Loughlin, John Leslie Noble (Box 10)
    - Osborne, Hubert (Box 10)
    - Ott, J. Benjamin (Box 10)
    - Ould, Hermon (Box 10)
    - Pallis, Marco (Box 10)
    - Parker, Henry Taylor (Box 10)
    - Patch, Blanche Eliza (Box 10)
    - Pattun, Fred (Box 10)
    - Paxinou, Katina (Box 10)
    - Payne, Ben Iden (Box 10)
    - Peabody, Josephine Preston (Box 10)
    - Peacey, Howard (Box 10)
    - Peach, Lawrence du Garde (Box 10)
    - Peacock, Walter (Box 10)
    - Pearson, George (Box 10)
    - Peel, Lady Delia Adelaide Margaret (Box 10)
    - Pemberton, Brock (Box 10)
    - Penlington, Zoë (Box 10)
    - Percy, S. Esme (Box 10)
    - Perrett, Eleanor P. (Mrs. George R. Perrett) (Box 10)
    - Peters, Augustus Dudley (Box 10)
    - Peters, Rollo (Box 10)
    - Phillips, May (Lidyard) (Box 10)
    - Phillpotts, Eden (Box 10)
    - Playfair, Sir Nigel Ross (Box 10)
    - Pleasance, K. L. (Box 10)
    - Plotkin, Abraham (Box 10)
    - Pocock, Guy Noel, ca. 1903 (Box 10)
      Poem.
    - Pohl, Elsa (Box 10)
    - Porter, Charlotte Endymion (Box 10)
    - Poston, Elizabeth (Box 10)
    - Poulton, Kay (Box 10)
    - Powys, John Cowper
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Browne, Maurice, 1917-1954; 2 folders (Box 10)
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen (Box 10)
        - Davies, Frederick (Box 10)
        - Underwood, Molly (Box 10)
        - Van Volkenburg, Juliet (Cooper) (Box 10)
      - Ana, 1915-1978 and undated (Box 10)
    - Price, Nancy (Box 10)
    - Pritt, Denis Nowell (Box 10)
    - Pryde, James Ferrier (Box 10)
    - Pulman, C. B. (Box 10)
    - Quilter, Roger (Box 10)
    - Quinn, John (Box 10)
    - Ramhorst, Ella Lemoa (Box 10)
    - Ranney, Dudley P. (Box 10)
    - Rarig, Arthur (Box 10)
    - Rathbone, Basil (Box 10)
    - Ravitch, Helen (Box 10)
    - Rawlings, Margaret (Box 10)
    - Ray, Eleanor (Kamb) (Box 10)
    - Raynal, Paul (Box 10)
    - Rea, Alex L. (Box 10)
    - Reed, Henry (Box 10)
      Of Stonegrave, York.
    - Rees, Phoebe Meirion (Box 10)
    - Reicher, Hedwiga (Box 10)
    - Reid, Norah (Box 10)
    - Reynolds, Cecil E. (Box 10)
    - Reynolds, James (Box 10)
    - Rice, Elmer L. (Box 10)
    - Rice, Warner Grenelle (Box 10)
    - Richardson, Sir Ralph David (Box 10)
    - Ridgeway, Peter (Box 10)
    - Riefstahl, Mary Elizabeth (Box 10)
    - Riev, Nelly (Box 10)
    - Riggs, Leslie C. (Box 10)
    - Riggs, Stephen W. (Box 10)
    - Roberts, Kathleen (Box 10)